Guide to the George Eliot and George Henry Lewes Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Section III. Letters to/about GEORGE ELIOT & GEORGE HENRY LEWES
  - Buchanan, Robert, 1841-1901
    - to GHL, 1864 Jun 30
      - ----, 1864 Aug 6 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1864 Aug 15 (Box 7)
  - Buddee, Karl
    - to GE, [1870 Sep 18-19] (Box 7)
      Incomplete copy by GE; in German. Tinker 968
  - Burne-Jones, Sir Edward Coley, 1833-1898
    - to J.W. Cross, [1880 Dec 24] (Box 7)
    - ----, [1880] Dec 28 (Box 7)
      Tinker 967
  - Burne-Jones, Georgiana (Macdonald), Lady, 1840-1920
    - to J.W. Cross, 1880 Dec 23
      - ----, 1881 Mar 26 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1885 Jan 27 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1885 Apr 10 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1885 Apr 14 (Box 7)
    - to GE, [1870] Aug 2
      - ----, 1873 Jun 23 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1878 Dec 5 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1879 Jul 1 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1880 May 6-7 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1880 Jun 16 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1880 Aug 31 (Box 7)
  - Burton, Sir Frederic William, 1816-1900
    - to GE, 1863 Jul 9
      - ----, 1868 Jun 21 (Box 7)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1882 Jan 27 (Box 7)
  - Caird, Edward, 1835-1908
    - to GHL, 1874 May 10 (Box 7)
    - ----, 1877 May 20 (Box 7)
  - Call, Elizabeth Rebecca (Brabant) Hennell, 1811-1898
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 3 (Box 7)
    - ----, [1880] May 21 (Box 7)
  - Call, Wathen Mark Wilks
    - to J.W. Cross, 1882 Jul 22 (Box 7)
  - Campbell, P.W.
    - to GE, 1878 Oct 16 (Box 7)
  - Carlyle, Jane Baillie (Welsh), 1801-1866
    - to GE, 1859 Feb 20 (Box 7)
      Tinker 969
  - Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881
    - to GHL, 1855 Nov 3 (Box 7)
  - Cassell & Co. Ltd.
    - to Ellis & Ellis, 1931 Feb 13 (Box 7)
  - Chapman, John, 1821-1894
    - to James Martineau, 1851 Aug 29 (Box 7)
      Draft in the hand of GE
    - to GE, 1857 Jan 15 (Box 7)
    - to Johanna von Heyligenstaedt, 1859 Jun 21
      - ----, 1859 Sep 26 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1860 Oct 18 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1860 Nov 17 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1861 Jul 25 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1861 Aug 5-6 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1861 Oct 24 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1861 Nov 16 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1861 Nov 20 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1861 Dec 9 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1862 Feb 20 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1862 Mar 6 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1862 Mar 11 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1862 Mar 24 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1862 Apr 8 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1862 Jul 4 (Box 7)
      - ----, 1863 May 1 (Box 7)
    - to Pres (his second wife), 1880 Jan 26 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1880 Jan 29 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1880 Feb 5 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1880 Feb 10 (Box 8)
  - Chapman, Susanna (Brewitt), 1808-1892
    - to John Chapman, [1851] Oct 31 (Box 8)
  - Chapman and Hall
    - Estimate for a 2/-series, 1866 (Box 8)
  - Chapman-Huston, Desmond
    to Elinor Ouvry
    - with draft of Mrs. Ouvry's reply, 1935 Nov 5 (Box 8)
  - Child, Lydia Maria, 1802-1880
    - to GE, 1879 Jan 26 (Box 8)
  - Christie, J.M.
    - to [GE], 1867 Sep 20 (Box 8)
  - Clark, Harriet
    - to Elinor Ouvry, [1928] Apr 3 (Box 8)
  - Clark, William George
    - to GE, [187-] Nov 18 (Box 8)
  - Clarke, Edward, 1838- (GE's nephew)
    - to GE, 1868 Jul 31 (Box 8)
  - Clarke, Emily Susannah, 1844-1924, (GE's niece)
    - to GE, [1859] Oct 20 (Box 8)
    - ----, 1871 Sep 16 (Box 8)
    - ----, 1878 Dec 2 (Box 8)
    - ----, 1878 Dec 13 (Box 8)
    - ----, 1880 May 6 (Box 8)
  - Clifford, William Kingdon, 1845-1879
    - to GHL, [1872?] (Box 8)
  - Clodd, Edward, 1840-1930
    - to GE, 1879 Dec 27 (Box 8)
  - Cohn, Albert
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1883 Dec 14 (Box 8)
    - to GHL, 1873 Jun 18 (Box 8)
  - Combe, George, 1788-1858
    - to GHL, 1856 Sep 14 (Box 8)
  - Congreve, Maria (Bury), 1836?-1915
    - to GE, 1859 May 1
      - ----, 1859 May 21 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1859 Jun 8 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1859 Jun 24 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1859 Aug 27 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1860 May 17 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1860 Dec 28 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1878 Dec 1 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1878 Dec 13 (Box 8)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1878 Dec 2 (Box 8)
  - Congreve, Richard, 1818-1899
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 9 (Box 8)
  - Conran, Edith
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 11 (Box 8)
  - Coombs, D.J.
    - to GE, 1873 Nov 25 (Box 8)
  - Costello, Dudley, 1803-1865
    - to GHL, 1858 Feb 10 (Box 8)
  - Courtauld, Samuel, 1793-1881
    - to John Chapman, 1854 Nov 9 (Box 8)
    - ----, 1855 Nov 29 (Box 8)
  - Coventry Public Library, E. Austin Hinton, Librarian
    - to Elsie Druce, 1934 Feb 15 (Box 8)
  - Cowper-Temple, Georgiana (Tollemache), Lady
    - to GE [Entered in catalogue, [1878] Dec 11 (Box 8)
    - under Mount-Temple, Georgiana (Tollemache) Cowper-Temple, baroness, 1822-1901], [1879] Nov 18 (Box 8)
  - Craik, George Lillie, 1798-1866
    to GHL
    - Friday, [1858] (Box 8)
  - Cross, Eleanor, 1847-1895
    - to GE, [1880 Apr 12]
      - ----, [1880] Jul 20 (Box 8)
      - ----, [1880] May 6 (Box 8)
      - Tuesday, [1880? Jun] (Box 8)
    - to E.F.S. Pigott, [1880] May 6 (Box 8)
  - Cross, John Walter, 1840-1924
    - to an unidentified recipient, 1880 Dec 23 (Box 8)
    - to Barbara Leigh (Smith) Bodichon, 1881 Jan 13
      - ----, 1881 May 3 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1881 May 7 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1881 Jul 9 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1881 Aug 27 (Box 8)
    - to Lady Burne-Jones, 1880 Dec 22 (Box 8)
    - to Sir Frederic Burton, 1881 Feb 5
      - The portrait and I..., 1881 Feb 7 (Box 8)
      - I am just back..., 1881 Feb 7 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1885 Mar 16 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1885 Mar 18 (Box 8)
    - to Anna (Chalmers) Cross, 1872 Apr 13
      - ----, 1872 May 3 (Box 8)
    - to Mary Finlay Cross, 1880 Jun 1 (Box 8)
    - to Robert Evans, 1881 Feb 1
      - ----, 1881 Mar 3 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1882 May 16 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1882 Sep 17 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1883 Aug 6 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1883 Aug 15 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1884 Nov 24 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1885 Mar 28 (Box 8)
    - to Gertrude (Hill) Lewes, 1919 Mar 13
      Fragment in the hand of J.W. Cross of a quotation from a letter from Professor Tyndall to Dean Stanley about The Spanish Gypsy.
      - Photocopy of his will and its codicils., 1915 Oct 11- (Box 8)
      - ----, 1916 Jun 6 (Box 8)
      - Accompanied by 2 obituaries, one from The Times and the other not identified, 1924 Nov 4 (Box 8)
  - Cross, Mary Finlay, 1843-1902
    - to J.W. Cross, [1880] Jun 5 (Box 8)
    - to GE, [1880] May 10 (Box 8)
  - Cust, Lionel
    - to J.W. Cross, 1905 Feb 15 (Box 8)
  - Cyples, William
    - to GE, 1879 Dec 31 (Box 8)
      Accompanied by a copy of his "The Permutation of Ideas" [1868] inscribed to GH Lewes.
  - D'Albert Durade, Alexandre Louis François, 1804-1886
    - to J.W. Cross, 1885 Feb 15
      - ----, 1885 Feb 23 (Box 8)
        Tinker 970
    - to GE, 1859 Oct 23
      - ----, 1859 Nov 30 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1860 Feb 5 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1860 Mar 19 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1860 Sep 11 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1860 Nov 25 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1861 Jan 24 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1864 Mar 21 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1864 Jun 20 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1871 Sep 11 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1872 Oct 19 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1873 Oct 26 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1877 Jan 19 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1878 Dec 7 (Box 8)
  - D'Albert Durade, Julie (Covelle), 1800-1880
    - to GE, [1860] (Box 8)
    - ----, 1860 Jul 16 (Box 8)
  - David, Ernest
    - to GE, 1876 Nov 11 (Box 8)
      Enclosing a review of Daniel Deronda by Alexandre Weill
    - ----, 1877 Sep 12 (Box 8)
  - Delboeuf, Joseph Rémi Léopold
    - to GE, 1879 Feb 23
      - ----, 1879 May 23 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1879 Oct 14 (Box 8)
    - to GHL, 1878 Jul 10 (Box 8)
      Accompanied by Delboeuf's article, "Psychologie comparée. Le sens des couleurs chez les animaux" in La Revue Scientifique, 24 May 1879, inscribed to GE.
  - De la Rue, Warren
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 5 (Box 8)
  - Deutsch, Emanuel Oscar Menahem, 1829-1873
    - to GE, 1867 Aug 20 (Box 8)
    - ----, 1867 Oct 2 (Box 8)
    - ----, 1868 May 21 (Box 8)
  - Dickens, Charles
    - to GHL, 1853 Feb 25 (Box 8)
  - Dilke, Emilia Francis (Strong) Pattison, Lady, 1840-1904
    - to GE, 1874 Nov 30 (Box 8)
    - ----, [1875 Jan 10] (Box 8)
      Accompanied by an excerpt copied by Mrs. Pattison from the Livret du Salon quoting GE's "The Lifted Veil."
  - Dohrn, Anton, 1840-1909
    - to GHL, 1873 Feb 10 (Box 8)
  - Dolgoronsky, Olga
    - to J.W. Cross, 1889 Jul 3 (Box 8)
  - Druce, Anna Bowling Buchanan (Cross) (Mrs. Albert Druce), 1841-1921
    - to J.W. Cross, [1880] Jun 11-12 (Box 8)
  - Druce, Elsie
    - to Elinor Ouvry, 1925 Feb 3
      - ----, 1926 Feb 21 (Box 8)
      - ----, 1932 Oct 23 (Box 8)
    - Letters to Miss Druce, about GE's grave in Highgate Cemetery, from:
      - National Trust, 1946 Oct 22 (Box 8)
      - The London Society, 1946 Oct 30 (Box 8)
      - London Cemetery Co., 1946 Nov 2 (Box 8)
      - Mrs. H.M. Tonks (née Evans), 1946 Nov 6 (Box 8)
      - London Cemetery Co., 1946 Nov 8 (Box 8)
      - Ian Maclean, 1946 Nov 8 (Box 8)
      - National Trust, 1946 Nov 8 (Box 8)
      - Mrs. H.M. Tonks, 1946 Nov 11 (Box 8)
      - Daniel & Millward, 1946 Nov 18 (Box 8)
      - London Cemetery Co., 1947 Apr 30 (Box 8)
      - London Cemetery Co., 1947 May 2 (Box 8)
      - London Cemetery Co., 1947 May 9 (Box 8)
      - Mrs. H.M. Tonks, 1947 Jun 2 (Box 8)
      - Accompanied by a copy of a deed of sale (incompletely filled in) of GE's grave in Highgate Cemetery. (Box 8)
  - Du Maurier, George Louis Palmella Busson, 1834-1896
    - to C.L. Lewes, [1881] May 2 (or9?) (Box 8)
  - Duncan, Warren & Gardner
    - to William Blackwood & Sons, 1881 Feb 21 (Box 8)
      (Photocopy)
  - Edwards, Annie L.
    - to GE, [1873] Apr 11 (Box 9)
  - Eliot, George, Fellowship
    - "Suggested Rules" to Elinor Ouvry, 1930 Oct 31 (Box 9)
  - Ellensohn, G.
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 5 (Box 9)
  - Ellis & Ellis
    - Carbon of letter to A.P. Watt & Son concerning rights in GE's novels, 1926 Mar 2 (Box 9)
  - Engelmann, Julius
    - to Charles Lee Lewes, 1883 Dec 28 (Box 9)
  - Evans, Eleanor Mary, 18??-1923 (niece of GE)
    - to J.W. Cross, [1882] Sep 5 (Box 9)
  - Evans, Frederic Rawlins, 1842-1927 (nephew of GE)
    - to J.W. Cross, [1880] Dec 28 (Box 9)
    - ----, [1881] Mar 4 (Box 9)
    - ----, [1882] Aug 13 (Box 9)
      Tinker 971
    - ----, 1896 Mar 12 (Box 9)
  - Evans, Harriette (daughter of Robert Evans II)
    - to her brother Robert Evans, No year, Feb 17 (Box 9)
    - Valentines verses, 1849 (Box 9)
  - Evans, Isaac Pearson, 1816-1890 (brother of GE)
    - to J.W. Cross, 1880 Dec 24
      - ----, 1881 Jan 22 (Box 9)
      - ----, 1881 May 27 (Box 9)
      - ----, 1885 Jan 29 (Box 9)
      - ----, 1885 Feb 9 (Box 9)
      - ----, 1885 Mar 26 (Box 9)
    - to GE, 1880 May 17 (Box 9)
      Tinker 972
  - Evans, Mrs. Jane (of Sutton Coldfield)
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 12 (Box 9)
  - Evans, Jane (Attenborough) (Mrs. Robert Evans), 1815-1881
    - to GE, [1864] Mar 15 (Box 9)
  - Evans, Mary Spence (Brown) (Mrs. Edmund Brown)
    - to J.W. Cross, [1885] Mar 29 (Box 9)
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 11 (Box 9)
  - Evans, Robert, 1773-1849, (father of GE)
    Extract from the diary of Robert Evans for 22 Nov 1829, with two short notes, all in the hand of Eleanor Mary Evans and signed with her initials.
    Tinker 973
    - to Frances Lucy (Evans) Houghton, 1837 Jul 10 (Box 9)
    - Sunday, [1837?] (Box 9)
    - to Henry Houghton, 1837 Sep 10 (Box 9)
  - Evans, Robert, 1832-1911 (nephew of GE)
    - to J.W. Cross, 1880 Dec 26
      - ----, 1881 Mar 1 (Box 9)
      - ----, 1882 Mar 31 (Box 9)
      - ----, 1883 Aug 12 (Box 9)
      - ----, 1885 Feb 1 (Box 9)
    - to GE, 1866 Aug 13
      - ----, 1866 Sep 7 (Box 9)
  - Evans, Sarah (Rawlins) (Mrs. Isaac Evans) 1806-1881
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 5 (Box 9)
  - Evans, Thomas C.
    - to GE, 1859 Aug 10 (Box 9)
    - ----, [1859 Aug] (Box 9)
  - Eve, Florence Nightingale (Cross) (Mrs. Henry Weston Eve), 1857-1915
    - to J.W. Cross, [1880 May 7] (Box 9)
    - ----, [1880] May 21 (Box 9)
    - to GE, [1880 May 7] (Box 9)
  - Ewart, Mary A. (Box 9)
    Note, signed, about visit to GE, written on p. [3] of ALS from GE to Miss Ewart, 1880 Feb 7 pasted on inside front cover of Romola [Beinecke Library.1972.135].
  - Fawcett, Henry, 1833-1884
    - to J.W. Cross, 1880 Dec 27 (Box 9)
  - Fawcett, Millicent (Garrett) (Mrs. Henry Fawcett)
    - to J.W. Cross, [1880] Dec 24 (Box 9)
  - Fields, Annie (Adams) (Mrs. James Thomas Fields)
    - to GE, 1874 May 20 (Box 9)
    - ----, 1874 Aug 4 (Box 9)
    - ----, 1879 Feb 2 (Box 9)
  - Fitz-Gerald, Eliza
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 4 (Box 9)
  - Flower, Constance (de Rothschild)
    - to GE, 1879 Jan 1 (Box 9)
  - Forman, Emma (Leaming)
    - to GE, [1877?] (Box 9)
  - Foster, Sir Michael, 1836-1907
    - to GE, 1879 Jan 1 (Box 9)
  - Franklin, Lewis A.
    - to Nicolaus Trübner, 1874 Jun 23 (Box 9)
  - Freese, Theodor
    - to K.F.O. Westphal, 1870 Apr 1 (Box 9)
      Accompanied by a diagram of an electrical machine and a trans- lation by GHL of the letter.
  - Frese, Julius
    - to an unidentified recipient, 1857 Jan 22 (Box 9)
      fragment
  - Froude, James Anthony, 1818-1894
    - to GE, [1858] Jan 17
      - ----, [1858] Sep 26 (Box 9)
      - ----, [1859] Mar 13 (Box 9)
    - to GHL, No year Feb 7 (Box 9)
  - Gall, Rutland
    - to GE, 1859 May 10 (Box 9)
  - Gaskell, Elizabeth Cleghorn (Stevenson), 1810-1865
    - to GE, [1859] June 3 (Box 9)
  - Geddes, Emily (Bury) 1841-1929, (Mrs. James Cruickshank Geddes)
    - to GE, 1874 Jul 24 (Box 9)
  - Gendle, Elizabeth
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 4 (Box 9)
  - Gilman, Alice F.
    - to GE, 1879 Mar 30 (Box 9)
  - Gladstone, William Ewart
    - to [J.W. Cross?], 1880 Dec 27 (Box 9)
      Unsigned
  - Glyn, Isabella Dallas (Gearns), 1823-1889
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 3 (Box 9)
  - Goethe, Ottilie von, [1854 Aug 10] (Box 9)
    to GHL [photostat only]
  - Grant, Charles
    - I need scarcely say..., n.d. (Box 9)
    - I wish I could tell you..., n.d. (Box 9)
    - I cannot thank you sufficiently..., n.d. (Box 9)
  - Grant Duff, Sir Mountstuart Elphinstone, 1829-1906
    - to GE, 1873 Apr 1 (Box 9)
  - Grant Duff, Anna Julia (Webster), Lady
    - to GE, [1879] Jan 1 (Box 9)
  - Greville, Violet
    - to GE, [1880] Sep 30 (Box 9)
  - Griffiths, William
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 6 (Box 9)
  - Grove, Sir George, 1820-1900
    - to GE, [1876] Mar 27 (Box 9)
  - Guedalla, Haim, 1815-1904
    - to GE, [1876] Sep 25 (Box 9)
    - ----, [1876] Oct 1 (Box 9)
  - Gurney, Archer Thompson
    - to GE, 1857 May 14 (Box 9)
  - Gurney, Edmund, 1847-1888
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 17 (Box 9)
  - Gurney, Will
    - to GHL, 1860 Mar (Box 9)
  - Haldane, Elizabeth S.
    - With draft of Mrs. Ouvry's reply on last page, 1925 Jan 18 (Box 9)
    - ----, 1926 Jan 8 (Box 9)
    - ----, 1926 Feb 24 (Box 9)
    - ----, 1926 Mar 19 (Box 9)
    - ----, 1926 Mar 21 (Box 9)
    - ----, 1926 Apr 12 (Box 9)
    - ----, 1927 Mar 17 (Box 9)
    - ----, 1928 Mar 28 (Box 9)
  - Hall, William Henry Bullock, 1837-1904
    - to GE, 1879 Jan 15 (Box 9)
  - Hamer, S.S.
    - to GE, [1878 Dec] (Box 9)
  - Hamerton, Philip Gilbert, 1834-1894
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 7 (Box 9)
  - Hamilton, Constance M. (Lawrie)
    to J.W. Cross
    - with envelope, [1878] Dec 12 (Box 9)
    - ----, [1881] Jan 3 (Box 9)
  - Hare, John Strachey
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 3 (Box 9)
  - Harford, Frederick Kill
    - to GE, [1878] Jun 14 (Box 9)
  - Harris, Mary B.
    - to GE, 1879 Dec 10 (Box 9)
  - Harrison, Clifford
    - to GHL, [1877] May 1 (Box 9)
  - Harrison, Frederic, 1831-1923
    - to J.W. Cross, 1880 May 6 (Box 9)
      Tinker 989
    - ----, 1883 Jan 7 (Box 9)
    - ----, 1884 Jun 26 (Box 9)
    - ----, 1884 Dec 26 (Box 9)
    - ----, [1885?] Mar 9 (Box 9)
    - ----, [1885?] Mar 16 (Box 9)
    - ----, 1901 Apr 16 (Box 9)
      Tinker 990
    - to GE, [1866 Jan 11] (Box 9)
      Tinker 974
    - ----, [1866] Jan 18 (Box 9)
      Tinker 975
    - ----, [1866] Jan 27 (Box 9)
      Tinker 976
    - ----, [1866] Jan 29 (Box 9)
      Tinker 977
    - ----, [1866] Jan 30 (Box 9)
      Tinker 978
    - ----, [1866] Apr 17 (Box 9)
      Tinker 979
    - ----, [1866] Apr 27 (Box 9)
      Tinker 980
    - ----, [1866] May 2 (Box 9)
      Tinker 981
    - ----, [1866] May 16 (Box 9)
      Tinker 982
    - ----, [1866 May 26] (Box 9)
      Tinker 983
    - ----, [1866] May 29 (Box 9)
      Tinker 984
    - ----, [1866] Jun 1 (Box 9)
      Tinker 985
    - ----, [1866] Jul 19 (Box 9)
      Tinker 986
    - ----, [1867] Feb 5 (Box 9)
      Tinker 987
    - ----, [1868] May 25 (Box 9)
    - ----, [1868] Nov 11 (Box 9)
      Tinker 988
    - to William Henry (Bullock) Hall, 1880 Dec 23 (Box 9)
      Tinker 991
    - to C.L. Lewes, [1879] Mar 20 (Box 9)
  - Harvey, Alex
    - to GHL, 1858 Feb 24 (Box 10)
  - Haycroft, Alice G.G.
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 17 (Box 10)
  - Helps, Alice
    - to GE, 1880 May 15 (Box 10)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1878 Dec 3 (Box 10)
  - Helps, Sir Arthur, 1813-1875
    - to GHL, 1858 Feb 22 (Box 10)
  - Hennell, Charles Christian, 1809-1850
    - to Sara Sophia Hennell, 1845 Jul 17 (Box 10)
  - Hennell, Sara Sophia, 1812-1899
    - to GE, 1854 Nov 15 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1858 Jun 27 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1859 Apr 14 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1859 Jun 26 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1859] Jul 1 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1859] Aug 21 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1859] Sep 5 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1859 Sep 18] (Box 10)
    - ----, 1859 Oct 1 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1859] Oct 6 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1859] Oct 9 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1859] Oct 12 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1859] Dec 12 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1860 Jan 18 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1860 Jun 28 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1863] Aug 22 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1874 Apr 21 (Box 10)
      See: Bray-Hennell Extracts
      See: Lewis, Maria, for S.S. Hennell's note about GE's letters to Miss Lewis
  - Herkomer, Hubert
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1889 Sep 21 (Box 10)
  - Herzen, Alexandre, 1839-
    - to GE, 1879 Jan 16 (Box 10)
  - Hill, Caroline I.
    - to GE, [1873] Jan 26 (Box 10)
  - Hill, Caroline Southwood (Smith), (Mrs. James Hill)
    - to GE, 1879 Jan 18 (Box 10)
  - Hill, Florence
    - to Elinor Ouvry, 1928 May 18 (Box 10)
  - Hinton, Margaret
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 12 (Box 10)
  - Hodder & Stoughton (by Sir Ernest Hodder Williams)
    - to Elizabeth Haldane, 1926 Mar 18 (Box 10)
  - Holland, Sir Henry, 1788-1873
    - to GHL, [1858] Feb 17 (Box 10)
  - Holland, Sir Henry Thurston, 1825-1914
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 12 (Box 10)
  - Holland, Margaret Jean (Trevelyan), Lady
    - to GE, [1878] (Box 10)
      Friday
  - Holt, H.P.R.
    - to GE, 1879 Aug 3 (Box 10)
  - Holyoake, George Jacob, 1817-1906
    - to Herbert Spencer, 1878 Dec 15 (Box 10)
  - Hooper, Jane Margaret (Wynnard) (Mrs. George Hooper)
    - to GE, 1871 Nov 29 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1878 Dec 2 (Box 10)
  - Hopwood, Maud Southwood (Lewes) (Mrs. John Rowland Hopwood)
    - to Elinor Ouvry, [1928] Apr 3 (Box 10)
  - Houghton, Richard Monckton Milnes, 1st Baron, 1809-1885
    - to GHL, [1862?] Aug 22 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1865] May 5 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1870] May 3 (Box 10)
  - Howard, Rosalind Frances (Stanley), later Countess of Carlisle
    - to GE, 1873 Oct 13 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1880 May 17 (Box 10)
  - Howitt, Mary (Mrs. William Howitt), 1799-1888
    - to Mary Gillies, [1869] Nov 4 (Box 10)
  - Huddy, Mary Elizabeth (Lee)
    - to Elinor Ouvry, 1926 Jun 30 (Box 10)
      "Some Account of Mrs. Willim" enclosed in the above letter.
  - Hunt, Leigh, 1784-1859
    - to Margaret Gillies, [1846] May 12 (Box 10)
    - to GHL, [1838] Jul 12 (Box 10)
    - to GHL and Agnes (Jervis) Lewes, [1841] Feb 19 (Box 10)
    - to GHL, [1841?] Aug 4 (Box 10)
  - Hunt, Thornton Leigh, 1810-1873
    - to GHL, 1838 Jul 6 (Box 10)
  - Hutton, James (ed. Universal Review )
    - to GE, [1859] Jun 16 (Box 10)
  - Hutton, Richard Holt (ed. Spectator ), 1826-1897
    - to GE, 1863 Aug 6 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1863] Aug 10 (Box 10)
  - Hutchinson, Sir Jonathan, 1828-1913
    - to GE, 1874 Sep 10 (Box 10)
  - Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895
    - to GHL, 1858 Jul 18 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1864 Mar 21 (Box 10)
  - Inman, Mary Elizabeth
    - to GE, 1873 Oct 12 (Box 10)
  - Jackson, John Hughlings, 1835-1911
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 2 (Box 10)
    - to GHL, 1871 Mar 17 (Box 10)
  - Jacobs, Joseph
    - to GE, 1879 Aug 29 (Box 10)
  - Jerrold, Douglas, 1803-1857
    - Saturday, [1847?] (Box 10)
    - ----, [184?] Sep 14 (Box 10)
    - ----, [1848] May 14 (Box 10)
  - Jerrold, William Blanchard, 1826-1884
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 12 (Box 10)
  - Jevons, William Stanley, 1835-1880
    - to GHL, 1871 Apr 12 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1871 Apr 19 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1875 Mar 21 (Box 10)
  - Jewsbury, Geraldine Endsor, 1812-1880
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 7 (Box 10)
  - Joachim, Ellen (Mrs. Henry Joachim)
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 7 (Box 10)
  - Johnson, Rossiter
    - to J.W. Cross, 1885 May 27 (Box 10)
  - Jones, Owen, 1809-1874
    - to GE, 1868 Jul 30 (Box 10)
  - Jones, Thomas
    - to GE, 1879 Sep 15 (Box 10)
  - Jowett, Benjamin, 1817-1893
    - to GE, 1872 Aug 14
      - ----, 1878 Oct 20 (Box 10)
      - ----, [1878] Oct 24 (Box 10)
    - to J.W. Cross
      - Telegram, 1880 Dec 24 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1880 Dec 28 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1885 Jan 27 (Box 10)
    - to GHL, No year Jun 5 (Box 10)
  - Kaufmann, David, 1852-1899
    - to GE, 1879 Apr 13 (Box 10)
  - Kaye, Harriette
    - to GE, No year Dec 17 (Box 10)
  - Keep, Elizabeth Porter
    - to GE, 1880 Feb 23 (Box 10)
  - Kelly, Howard Atwood, 1858-1943
    - to Elinor Ouvry, 1922 Aug 22 (Box 10)
  - Kingsley, Charles
    - to GHL, 1859 Jan 8 (Box 10)
  - Kovalevsky, Sophie (i.e. Sonya Korvina-Krukorskaya, Mrs. Vladimir O. Kovalevsky), 1850-1891
    - ----, [1869 Oct 8] (Box 10)
  - Kovalesky, Vladimir
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 12 (Box 10)
  - L, C.A.
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 31 (Box 10)
  - Lane, John, The Bodley Head
    - (by Ronald Boswell) to Ellis & Ellis, 1926 Jan 26 (Box 10)
    - Carbon copy of reply from Ellis & Ellis, 1926 Feb 23 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1926 Apr 21 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1926 Apr 28 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1926 Apr 29 (Box 10)
  - Lang, Andrew, 1844-1912
    - to J.W. Cross, [1880] Dec 30 (Box 10)
      Tinker 994
  - Langford, Joseph Munt, 1809-1884
    - to GE, 1859 Oct 8
      - ----, 1859 Oct 12 (Box 10)
    - to GHL, 1859 Feb 8
      - ----, 1859 Aug 3 (Box 10)
  - Lankester, Phebe
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 3 (Box 10)
  - Lea, H.M.
    - to GE, 1872 Nov 21 (Box 10)
  - Lean, Florence Marryat
    - to GE, 1879 Feb 8 (Box 10)
  - Lehmann, Emil, 1829-1898
    - to GE, 1867 Oct 7 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1878 Dec 6 (Box 10)
  - Lehmann, Nina (Chambers) (Mrs. Frederick Lehmann)
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 6 (Box 10)
  - Lehmann, Rudolf
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 6 (Box 10)
  - Leslie, Seymour
    - to Elinor Ouvry, [1928] Apr 12 (Box 10)
  - Levi, David
    - to GE, 1880 Feb 3 (Box 10)
  - Lewes, Agnes (Jervis) (Mrs. G.H. Lewes), 1822-1902
    - to Elizabeth Gendle, [1862?] (Box 10)
  - Lewes, Charles Lee, 1842-1891
    - to Albert Cohn, 1883 Dec 11 (Box 10)
      draft
    - to J.W. Cross, 1883 Apr 2
      - ----, 1883 Sep 16 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1884 Dec 9 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1884 Dec 27 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1885 Jan 27 (Box 10)
      - Extract from GHL's journal for 28 Jan 1859 copied for J.W. Cross, [1883?] (Box 10)
    - to Agnes Jervis Lewes, 1857 Mar 1
      - ----, 1857 Sep 13 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1858 Jan 10 (Box 10)
    - to GE, [1859] Jul 24
      - ----, 1859 Sep 6 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1859 Nov 20 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1871 Jun 18 (Box 10)
    - to GE, 1871 Jul 2
      - ----, 1871 Jul 16 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1880 May 23 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1880 May 31 (Box 10)
    - to GHL, 1857 Mar 29
      - ----, 1857 Jul 18 (Box 10)
      - ----, [1858] Feb 16 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1858 Apr 21 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1858 Jun 6 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1858 Jul 25 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1858 Oct 10 (Box 10)